okay so today's the 6th of September
yeah
December sorry and we're at clique
offices and this is Christopher McPhee
talking and I'm here with my honored and
you work here at the clique yeah I work
a clique as a software engineer hmm so I
have some questions for you regarding
we're going to talk about API rate
lighter stuff we're gonna talk a little
bit about release notes and we kind of
talked a little bit about online
communities around software platforms
hmm and you looked at some material
beforehand so if we start with API
related things okay so when you're
looking at how important would you say
that API examples a documentation is for
a software platform probably one of the
most important things when it comes to
documentation because I would say most
for most people that's the first thing
you look at because if it's an API
you're not familiar with the examples
are the the way you actually want to get
familiar with how things are working so
when you look at a very examples why are
you trying to what are you looking for
like when you look up by examples what
is it what is it you want to find out I
don't know I guess it depends on what
I'm looking for sometimes it can be if
I'm looking at a specific method I want
to be able to find that quickly and to
have an example of how that thing works
in specific way and I guess it should be
clear examples consistent examples and
[Music]
yeah I don't know
but and and also that there's some
explanation not just code but also
explanation about what that code does
yeah some kind of documentation about
the methods and what they do and how
they should behave hmm
so it's it so would it's more of a it's
a mixture of trying to understand how
they are used and where they were used
or yeah yeah of course and copy paste
encoded that it's not something that is
good for code examples as well or just
to what do you mean for you mean for the
developer to be able to just copy paste
and try something out I think it's good
if you can get like if you can try
something out quickly just to see that
that's what you're that it works I guess
but it doesn't need to be a complete
example in which you know everything is
done for you hmm
it's more important of a concise example
we just what they're trying to explain
rather than a big one yeah I think it's
good to have it really depends on the
case sometimes it's nice to have both
like to use that example in the context
of something bigger but it it really
depends on the method if it's it
something something as simple as you
know you need to do a copy paste then
it's enough to just focus on that simple
method how to do a copy paste with this
API okay
because it doesn't really have a lot of
dependencies on other things so I think
it really depends when it comes to it's
not really API is but in click when it
comes to the scripting language when you
developed apps and things for example
there it's nice to have examples that
are within a bigger context so yeah it
kind of depends but I would
if I have to choose then it would be it
would be more concise examples that just
show you okay this is what I wanted to
know and I don't have to go searching
like they said in the context of click
it's new you have it a bigger example
when is it not when it's in what context
is better to have a smaller example then
it's like what makes click and they get
bigger yeah yeah so in this sense it
wasn't click as everything related to
click it was specifically because yeah I
always complain and other people I think
always complain with the documentation
regarding the app development and
scripting and in that case you need more
knowledge before you can jump into a
specific method so there you kind of
it's important to have more step-by-step
things it's more advanced we need yeah
yeah because you can't just you need
some prerequisite knowledge in order to
get to that okay so I think in every
documentation it's important if you know
that you need some some prerequisite
knowledge that it's not maybe very
common that it's nice to have those
examples as well or at least some links
or references to where can you learn
about that because it's yeah it can be
quite annoying when you get start
reading an explanation and then there's
ten ten things you don't even know what
they mean and it's nowhere explained so
how does it affect you if you're looking
at FBI examples and they're not very
good how does that affect your work well
if I have a choice to find something
else to use then I would just do that if
I don't have a choice well usually you
have a choice I mean usually you can
choose between different different
options
which API used to go go to do this the
same thing so in that case if you select
one thing and then you see the
documentation is bad usually you just
scrape it and turn to something
different had the situation like that
recently when we started and that we
actually implemented stuff using this
I forgot how it's called doesn't really
matter but we had the written code and
everything and yeah it was all the
working examples but more and more we
were working with it we realized the
documentation is really lacking and it
was difficult once you get into problems
to fix them so we actually just scraped
that and started all over again with the
difference so with a different solution
so yeah it's it definitely affects the
developer in a bad way so looking at the
material is there anything that you saw
that okay this is very important or this
is not important or is there some key
aspects that you're missing here that
you usually look at it was a lot of
pictures yeah but yeah it's definitely
good that there is some there were some
examples of how to do well in this case
yeah very basic example like the this is
how you get started that's nice and then
some example of okay this is one step
more a bit more advanced so I think
that's a nice way to present it to have
like the very basic one and then to go
into this is how you can modify things
so I definitely like that and yeah I
like that you have in meta descriptions
that you have listed like the parameters
and their types and description that's
always helpful
so is that something that is something
that should always exist or is it some
kind of like a bonus this is good if it
exists I would say it's something that
should always exist so I mean it seems
like a very basic basic description to
have like when you want to use method
you want to know which parameters since
has what type they can be and yeah what
do they actually do so for me that's
kind of a must examples as well like
always
yeah release notes that's always good to
have just to make sure you're not using
something that doesn't work anymore or
will be deprecated then once you upgrade
hmm later so another thing about you've
touched upon this a bit to have working
code quickly is that something that is
important to you I think it's nice to
have working code quickly to have some
kind of a basic example quickly but then
once of course it would usually need
more work and more time when you want to
have something more advanced
but it's nice to be able to say okay
this is how I can at least get the setup
part done and I can see that I get
something out so you don't have to spend
the day and then oh this this doesn't
work at all yeah so I think having some
kind of a basic working example it's
important so in what situation are you
willing to accept not something working
code quickly is it always needed to have
just the getting basics okay this is
rendering and then don't what bounced oh
can you wait for a long time I guess if
I know that it's something that
definitely works that it doesn't matter
I do I
need to be the one testing it so it's
something that's how do you say it's
kind of a standard you know people are
using this and it works I'm not gonna
run into some trouble where oh this is
very experimental that someone wrote and
yeah I need to be the one testing it so
I guess in that case it doesn't really
have to be a quick working example hmm
because I'm already aware okay maybe
there is even a community around the
solution so yeah maybe that's that's one
reason but you you said that early that
he scraped and started over because of
the documentation being poor so that was
more you work is with something new then
did you have started what working code a
issue there or just that is so that this
wasn't scalable if this documentation is
poor yeah it's so exactly it was it was
you could get a quick working example
and that's quick in that case quickly
and you could do the basic things
quickly and it worked well but after a
while every time you ran into a problem
and you wanted to fix it and you look
into the documentation it's like it
doesn't say anything here okay and if
you try to google it it's you know maybe
you'll find something maybe you don't so
you're kind of left on your own which is
not a very nice thing or something like
that does like the answer does exist in
the documentation but you need to search
for it for half an hour because it's not
ordered in a correct way or it's very
inconsistent or I don't know
so after kind of how do you say after
having the same problem multiple times
then we realized okay if this continues
happening you just keep losing time
time you want to fix something so we
kind of scraped it and did the
investigation okay what are our other
options and in this case let's try to
look at the documentation straight away
and see if all of the problems we had
with the older one are now gonna be
mixed so what do you say that working
code quickly is if the documentation is
good and they are examples are good will
you always have working code quickly
those links yeah I there definitely
linked yeah the better the documentation
is the easier it will be for you to get
get up and running I mean but obviously
as I said then the other way around uh
support working code quickly it doesn't
mean that the documentation will be good
yeah yeah in that case it doesn't so
yeah it kind of the good documentation
brings a lot of good things with it and
the bad documentation will bring a lot
of bad things but yeah I guess even in
bad documentation it's it's possible to
have basic examples but then once you
get into the more advanced stuff then it
fails you hmm
so the documentation it's a very key
part of it effects everything yeah okay
so if we move over more to talk about
release notes in general how often would
you say that you look at release notes
not very often really but it's usually
not me who and who has to decide between
like which software we are using or
which solutions which api's so I guess
it's not so often that I did I look at
it because of that
but yeah but I think it's still it's
still important to be able to find
release notes because eventually you
will want to like you want to upgrade
whatever software you're using and in
that case if you don't have
documentation you can easily run into
trouble if you don't have release notes
like this and so when you end up looking
at released under what circumstances
since you're not as you said the decider
to upgrade when you look at them why how
come you do that it's really for when it
comes to api's even not when if we take
the context that you're working on
something privately for example yeah I
guess yeah if you if you work on
something privately and then in that
case it will make more sense to look at
release notes but at the same time if
you're look if you're working on
something privately that's like just it
doesn't need to go into production or
something then you don't care too much
about if you're using a deprecated
method or not so yeah but I think when
it comes to I mean I can talk about in
the context of since our team is working
with API governance and the entire work
kind of the entire how you say job let's
say job where the goal is to present the
API changes and to make sure that the
customers that are using click API is
know what has what has changed between
releases because for them when they want
to upgrade to a new version of clixsense
that's very important so from from that
perspective looking at how how much
other people are injured
in having us presents that then it seems
like it's quite important yeah so what
is important to have in release notes I
guess it's important to have enough
details so that people are know people
know what what has happened between
releases for us we usually just and I
think most they just present kind of
what has what has changed if you have
new methods or new ways of doing things
and if you are supposed to avoid some
methods that you were using before so in
the material we have a very detailed
release note and very non detailed do
you see any observe downs with either
version yes yeah so here in the short
release notes when you have like the new
updated you don't really know what has
changed if one of these has been updated
so it doesn't say from it doesn't say
which one of these are completely new
which are updated and how they are
updated so that's something I that would
be my first question like I don't know
what has happened I just know something
has changed but it's what exactly I have
and then in the deprecated one you see
that four methods have been deprecated
but then if you have the if you have
used these methods in your code it
doesn't say what you should do instead
hmm so you're kind of left wondering
okay how am I supposed to fix my code
and I think this was fixed in the big
change lock yeah you have a list of the
Prakriti methods and you
specify what you should use instead yeah
even having the reasoning why you remove
something I think I think that's nice
when you defecate it kind of builds how
you say it builds trust when you can
explain why we did this change as if we
took the bigger version is it too
detailed is to like it or is it like how
it should be in quotations you have an
issue I think when it comes to release
notes if you would choose between having
not enough and too much it's better to
have too much I mean if it's like a few
pages or like a screen you usually know
what you want to look for so it's easy
to find even if it's a big big text
button here yeah I think it's nice it
seems like I wouldn't have it I wouldn't
need this yeah having bugs and talking
about when it was introduced so if there
are if the release notes are poorly
written how would they affect you I
think it's bad when it comes to kind of
the trust I mentioned between whoever is
using the API and whoever is developing
if it's a big company
such as click I know it's always really
big it's a big deal in a bad way if if
you upgrade to a new version of cents
and all of a sudden things are not
working I think it reflects really
poorly on the company and yeah it's
definitely a big deal
are there any other way of obtaining
this kind of information then release
notes or is that the only is that the
go-to way of finding out this finding
out kind of the changes between releases
yeah some companies take more care of
release notes and some don't but if you
don't have good release notes these
companies still exist - they still do
they have it some other way of
presenting this or is it just that they
have poor release notes yeah I'm not
sure what the other way would be I guess
depends on how you call it but yeah
there should be some way of finding out
what has happened in between releases I
would say so if we move over to and talk
about online communities and study
[Music]
so how do you take help from online
communities when working all the time
all the time yeah so so how important is
it for you when you work with software
there there is an online community
around it I think it's quite important
because sometimes even when you have a
documentation that's average or even
good it's always nice to have online
communities because you have then people
that's run into the same issues as you
do and I think it's enough to be in a
community it can be either on github
like you have opened issues on the
repository something as small as that or
just enough users that use the software
so you get for example and Stack
Overflow you can see issues of people
using the same thing it doesn't have to
be like a specific site that's dedicated
just to that product I think online when
it comes to online community it's like
anywhere on the internet but yeah I
think it's definitely important so even
even if the documentation was flawless
you still want a on my community around
it yeah I think it's still nice to have
an online community because then you see
that people are actually using using it
like the documentation can be perfect
but if no one is using this then why
should I so is it important to feel like
you're a part of a community yeah I
would say so
so why is it important then what happens
if you're working with a software that
doesn't have an online community how
does that make you feel I don't know it
seems like as I said like why am I the
only one using this that will be kind of
my question if I try to if I find I know
some software something
Pearson product and I can't find anyone
else using that thing I would it would
be like okay there's something wrong
there's something that fit so I think in
in that sense it's important to feel
like okay there are other people using
it other people that maybe have run into
the same issues and have solved the same
issues and you have someone also to turn
to kind of when you run into problems so
are they an a can you think of if you
tried to think of communities in
encounter that you liked and counted
communities that you didn't like what
are the differences between these two
communities examples of communities that
I didn't like you know think of the
things that are when you come into a
community that you feel like are like
this community some aspects that that
community had that you were like okay
this is this is positive yeah I'm mature
in the sense of like working with api's
because for me when I say in that sense
it's not like a specific place you go to
and you are talking only about it's it's
just having people that are using it and
it can be as I said on github or in
Stack Overflow or yeah wherever it's
important that it feels alive the
community yeah yeah that's for sure and
is it is it important that it feels
helpful yeah yeah I mean if if you see
that there are people or there is some
type of online community but there's
either very little people or people that
are not not active in it then it's
really not useful in the end and yeah
you
to be able to engage with other people
it's important that the software the
company connected to the software that
you're using that they're part of the
community yeah I think that's always
good I think it I don't think it's
necessary that they are part of the
community but I think it it would make
the the consumer feel better about using
the product and feel yeah again coming
back to the trust and the relationship
between the the product and the user so
it's it can't be a bad thing I would say
okay so is there a difference if you're
using is something big like a software
platform compared to something small
like a library what do you expect from
the online community
yeah I think it's definite there's
definitely a difference I mean for for
something small like a library you
usually yeah you don't need the same
level of interaction basically and
usually it's something that you will
just use a few times and don't think
about it but when it comes to the
platform it's probably something you
interact with constantly hmm so you kind
of want to have yeah then it's more
important to have a bigger community and
online community community or even a
separate space just for just for the
platform itself I'm more important with
only but the bigger it is the more
important yeah yeah I would
I mean when it comes to a small library
basically if you find something on
github to me what I look at is that it's
updated it doesn't really need to have
an own
and community around it as long as you
see that it's still ongoing and that
it's not that when it comes to updates
so yeah it's the size matters yeah so it
like overall what is it that you want
from an online community I guess I can
think about it in terms of click sense
and that type of community but yeah I
think I would like to have yeah activity
and people interacting with each other
and having questions and examples and
yeah
is there anything we've you want to ask
me or something you thought about that
you thought I'd ask that yeah I haven't
or something that you I don't know
nothing that I can think of then I think
that I've got all the answers I need
okay great thank you very much