okay today's date is the 14th of
December 2018 and we are here at click
offices and this is Christopher McAfee
talking and I'm here with you know
system and bring you're gonna talk a
little bit about mainly three topics API
sin general and release notes and online
communities around software platforms so
in general
how important would you say that API
documentation is if I start working with
something I think it's really important
actually because I've started with
different products and when and your
thought about the products quality of
the projects the funds item in it it's
hard connection today hate documentation
home assistant fresh in mind we said
using right now which I don't like at
all after a couple of hours in it it's
really hard to find some stuff you
forget the documentation it's not yeah I
think it was scattered and it was I
couldn't find everything I wanted so it
it seems to be around in blogs and posts
I were ok but they are one date in time
and since it's not a stable product it's
0.8 something something they might not
work and then I want to go to the main
page and I could find stuff there but I
think y'all were lacking examples or
liking the full picture to really get
what I wanted mmm that's a problem so
when you look at API documentation
what are you generally looking for what
do you want from me and documentation
and places the first of all examples
just like a lot of people and then so
first examples then it's the more
broader picture it does it look like
something I would understand or is it's
it's scattered a lot of different
terraces and I think the reason for that
is
here you're looking at so many different
small products in the word so before you
want to invest a lot of time in it you
try to or you maybe you do it without
knowing but you assess the quality based
on what you see the first five minutes
or something so you you start looking
into it and yes you shouldn't play down
look and feel on that because that if
it's fresh in you and updated yes it's
good and it's positive if it looks like
they are asking others to continue so I
think that's a positive thing as well
but I think it goes down to examples and
then does it feel full is it is there
enough things can I see in the beginning
that all it looks like it's covers the
ideas I had about this so it's not if I
click on something it's like yeah
there's you have to look into this
ripple to find this to find this or even
worse it's in French it's it's pending
near translation can you do the use
Google Translate anyone know you
mentioned API samples they were very
important to you they are because since
I'm lazy I want to get something started
fast and then I want to invest and I
think that's the the reason is for me to
get caught up in something if I if I
want to invest I can invest as much time
as I can depending part but but to know
if I should do it I tend to look at
examples and ideas how to accomplish
something because I want to know do I
need to write like 20 lines of code to
do it or is it free and if it's free is
it's actually doing what I want to
really do I need to do a lot of weird
stuff with the three lines to make it
work hmm so do you
as it having working out quickly is
important to you do you use the that's
the is that the main thing I use the
examples for to just copy paste to have
something going or I think it's to get
started mmm because
I like the idea of having something in
build up on that and I very rarely think
about okay let's use this bakery and
then I read through the whole API and
then I start working no I go to the
first example I can find attacked me in
the example we copy paste it and then I
don't get there I run it cool it looks
like this and then okay what does this
method you and then I go and look at
that mess okay that's not and then I do
something more and then I realized that
maybe I should know a little bit for me
because I'm just patching here and then
I thought it tend to read a little bit
more about it maybe how we should do it
that's all okay I like to play around
before I and I guess I'm not I'm not
like a senior developer working on our
feature I go to release soccer so it's
also because I'm it's hobby products I'm
looking mmm
so when are you willing to accept not
having working code quickly if if I have
an assignment I really won't need know
what to do and I have some time I know
good for this and maybe it's it's a more
complex task and I know that I need to
Seoul
so I have already thought in my mind
that I need to invest more than like
here's two hours for this to get started
maybe I understand this is I'm going to
do a new scheduling system for releasing
that and I know I know enough they
require some writing in our state
machine or something that I know okay I
already know that I need to that's quite
a long time and I had heard that this is
a good API or this is a good product
then I would start to work um you know
so one of the things we're trying to
understand is what exactly is good
documentation so if we use the examples
is there something there that you
thought of okay this is something I'll
always expect from me good documentation
is there something missing something
made that made you react I think that
was a class or something where it there
was not an explanation
if it was sake that was one which only
had information in about see here I
think it was Baker API where they it
doesn't say what's here
or if it was to suit this super and you
know I read I could get more from the
release notes than I could from the real
documentation no I don't like that
because they it's good with a release
but it's one item in time so I want the
real documentation to actually mirror
that and I think it was when you created
an Indian the super end euro sound like
nothing there was no information about
that in the real I think it was only
Creighton yeah I don't think there's any
things that actually is that it came
into the super end in here but then you
called my intention attention apparently
because I was looking more for more
information yeah just example well that
was fun thing yeah I think it was
getting a when you created a new Baker
what you you're supplying the engine but
there's no explanation or the
constructor of the maker I was missing
that but if we talk more in general
about how we can should construct a
documentation is there anything is there
aught of any red flags when you see you
encounter a new software platform and
read the documentation are there any red
flags that you think ok this is if you
have a lot of proprietary parameters or
something which or list just listed
without any description on it I think
that's bad I also don't like if there is
no examples as I said before I really
like to have some example in the
beginning of a class showing or whatever
it is library something just showing
this is a simple example and then
you can use that to navigate down so a
simple one maybe I'm not the worst one
as well but have something like that in
the beginning is really important for me
how much of a should they be example be
more of a snippet or should it be put in
a context more how much of a context is
needed
I think it's depends on what type of
area it is if it's uh if it's a utility
library I mean that's a snippet is good
enough and if it's an item doing sorry
if it's let's say yeah we have those
products which are that's a reading
statistics from github for just look at
today and there they had an example this
is how we should do it and okay that's a
good example I have two factor
authentication what do i do nothing but
it's good enough I can understand how
big the library looks like Mason example
what I can do then I search further from
my special case which is outside example
so that was good for adapter one if if
there would be a full solution where I
had to install something to get it going
then I would assume that there was an
example somewhere because if if the
first thing is to I think that is the
speed to run something neuro determinant
so in our case in clique or would be
that if there wouldn't be any easy way
to set up the engine and quickly pull it
down I wouldn't bother because it's too
long time for me to okay now I have to
download something a feeling a for I
don't know a lot of stuff before I can
even get it running the small snippet I
have here
that's dangerous I think then you're
into this that prove I have to assign a
lot of time on it make sure that I make
it methodically and set up my ID that's
okay so the the size of the example
depends on the context of the yes so I
would say in most cases it's how fast I
can get something after running I will
have a lot better feeling about the
stuff if there's
has made very fast guide on just getting
something else then I can evaluate if I
would like to take this or one of the
three other items I found for this area
and we need to do if it's like a helper
library somebody'd see crucial I was
there because it if it would be an
external course or a song if I had reach
my show she is probably one which is
most popular and then there is free
which are popular them it needs to be
very quick easy way to get it running
for me to understand okay I should use
this one hmm I didn't mention him before
we start the interview what is your role
here at click I'm a development manager
for the click core team I'm not
developer for saying here wannabe hobby
and my education so what is your tasks
during the day I say so I I would say in
this this form here it's other people
manager and I'm and I think the roles or
scrum master or tried one part of a
tried which means that I'm part of the
planning the work but also about
suggesting solutions or priorities in
the team a little bit of product I ought
to get a bit of architect and a product
designer so it's a mix of those things
and development is I would say it's a
minimal part I use it because I like to
understand what we're doing in the team
and of interest I think in my role you
could get out a gift away without
knowing anything but you had to work in
a different way
mmm-hmm so in as part of your role you
don't have to read a lot of
documentation it's more when you're
working on side projects yes so it's if
I'm doing something in the code here
I'm trying to do sometimes I do it of
course but it's not my main no it's not
my part of the work hmm so but you're
like if click were to use a new software
platform you're still part of the
decision-making to use that platform or
are you taking listening to for example
architects and what they want to use and
you approve that or what's your rosin
yeah I'm part of it no I will rely if an
architect know that I want this because
of that I would because I would never
say anything against them if it's if I
don't have any person and so no that's
true I would probably suggest and based
on my experience suggests what I believe
is my idea of a good platform do you
think it is working card quickly just a
consequence of good documentation and
API examples or is it a separate aspect
no I think it's the same actually yeah I
think it's there every library needs to
sell itself and proved its use and I
think one way is to do it like that you
could have a the most simple one and
that will be a lot harder to sell to
people if it's not easily
[Music]
because we if we it would be interesting
to get a in this interviews I'm talking
directly to you architects and
developers and such but now we have a
manager role here which isn't as you say
directly involved in the documentation
reading in its work role so would you
say that you how much of an interest in
your work role do you take in API
documentation of a software platform
that would be used in the product for
example the platform for how we write
documentation or we could take we could
take both examples like if click were to
use another software platform in in its
product and it had to be approved and
all that how much of an interest you
take in your working role for that I
think I think it's hard to say how much
but I take interest in it
mmm because I that's a simple one like a
UI framework or something like that I
want to know why we're choosing a
special framework and I think it's it's
twofold one is of course the one which
are important my role will this be
something which is valuable not just
today but in two years is it something
which works well with competence we have
the team and in the surroundings which
is something weird because it's found we
have to have a really good really simple
so so those are and then of course how
live that one is if he ever is starting
to maybe not in the my current role but
in my previous role where we bought the
software platforms then it was very
important that they are maintained
correctly and they are cost efficient
and that we get the support we need hmm
so all those questions are very
important to me now and then I would say
the rest is just my technical interest
feel it's not obliged but it's fun to
know about those though so that's the
other part but not so specific so it's
those things you mentioned is that
something that if there's some things
that only managers care about that
developers or architects wouldn't care
about when using a when it comes to
documentation I think that vapors tend
to play down the need for production it
could be that it's not that it's missed
out but at least in some places it's it
looks good if they it's fun to work with
it's good and I totally understand that
but sometimes it could be that you also
have have it a factory environment and
if something breaks down in that Factory
you will lose a lot of money each
minutes or so then you have to look into
a lot of other stuff like is there any
support contracts here which make sure
that this contact or there is a
percentage of times they're going to
happen because that's going to be a
discussion I have if I buy that sort of
support contract I would think
developers don't really want to talk
about those things there it's not there
a deal it's more or less purchase
purchasing discussion and like support
discussion and that me as a developer I
think you know I'm more responsible for
those so in my current role we don't
have that many of those because we're
using mostly open source code work in
open source world where there are other
things that play which is more important
like how well is this adopted by the
majority of local sort word and how much
maintenance is it and so on and I was a
historically it's not there the
developer the manager's primary
knowledge so here I depend a little
moron architects women taking those
decisions and maybe that's also why I
want to dig more into this because I
need to understand so I can be support
when when we're taking such decisions
mm-hmm
if we move over to release notes how
often would you say that you look at
release we're doing automatic upgrades
okay okay you have to see how it's done
so as I went into the other it's a
failed test okay I need to understand
why and then there was a link to the
release notes where I can see why and
that's all oh this is nothing
so that's that's thing otherwise it I
always say it's for my if I'm doing a
hobby product I might do it if it's I
know it's zero point version because
that might break break my way existing
corporation mmm but it's hobby so yeah
it's it's not that social well okay
because once again it's interesting to
see if release notes matter at all to
managers because we'll get the
perspective of architects and developers
from other interviews so do you think
general managers in general or you care
about release notes I would say from
from a manager perspective I care if it
breaks my stuff and if I need to add any
resources to this then that's my
perspective so nothing detailed like I
said that's not something that we look
into the furniture so if I'm going to if
we only talk about okay should we
upgrade to this solution I would post it
and I would participate in a meeting
where we took the decision then I would
be interested mmm because I want to know
how big of a change and how much time do
we need to invest in such a change so
that's very important
and so for major releases that I think
that's the most important for a manager
small patches I don't think they are
only important if something has mmm so
in the material we had a year two
extremes
one very short version and were quite
elaborate version because it's when it
comes to writing release notes it's a I
mean you have to a company has to spend
time and therefore money in order to
have more thorough release notes and
it's a balance to between these two how
much should you write do you have any
opinion on how much I think the short
one for imaginary I think that was
enough that there changes in this area
okay there we are
it looks like they they've added some
stuff and are we using the differ kg
stuff so so from a manic perspective I
think that's that's enough for me if a
little bit further I think when I read
the more detailed version I think that
it was good but I suspected that to be
in the real documentation is there so
for me it would be we have added these
stuff here's a link to the documentation
where it's I don't know mmm I think okay
so maybe more like okay you can't use
this form or use this new them all the
if not how you use an example states in
the region documentation mmm otherwise
you delicate so again from a manager
perspective when you decided to use a
new platform then it has to be approved
its release that's something that will
be looked at
before as part of the are we gonna use
this yeah I think that matiee the patch
ones I think being your changes like
that sometimes have other presentations
not in the release notes section it's
more like this new feature to have all
these many features and I'm sure would
probably look at that and see if it
matches their need and then probably
also architects and developers to tell
how much work they needed to put in to
fulfill the rest of the stuff the
deprecated stuff was known so I don't
think the manager it's even even before
like even before something has been
adopted you probably all probably check
ok that it's like the pricing you'll
infect II like lore surrounding it and
maybe it'll check out how is the
permutation how is it support but you
probably not check ok are the release
notes gonna be good when we're gonna
need them in one year probably not
I think that's unfortunately not to say
it's I probably should and then I have
to back a little bit on one thing since
I also have a scrum master role as a
manager which is not normal but in this
company we have it I would be interested
in what has actually changed when I came
into that solution so first I would take
the decision on a modular but if I get
into scrum master and then are more into
an operative mode and then I need to
know okay what what type has chance do
what deprecated Partizan then I would
probably read it together office it's a
little bit of a mixed role that's why
maybe it's mixed
mmm we can move over to a white
community night
so in general when I just say that a
software has an online community what
does that mean to you active discussions
that people are asking question and
they're getting answers quickly and
preferably not an active there are
people out there helping so in
communities that you like what did they
have in common that they are polite
first and they're there they are
elaborate answers to questions if
someone comes with a problem also on
there are people answering to the right
level because sometimes it could be
people who misuse this but I have to
show something to my manager please do
this for me I don't think those but you
should at least support out here some
help but to get you stormed here you
have this thing yeah so is it important
that the community feels alive that's a
very and also as you said they take
immunity must be helpful then it helpful
and but also polite yeah Politis that
I've seen some communities they are an
exception but they could be like yeah as
I said read the fucking that people are
trying and I think that's scaring people
away yeah supposed to be very complex
and cool but it's not helping if you're
inviting we
like that with that turn you away from
if you'll just stop me I was using a
software platform I need to Google
something and you realize okay this is
the kind of yeah it's a decision which
goes a lot of indicators even if it's
like that then you have bad communicator
documentation that needs to know that
really and because as community it could
be either be like for a click we have to
branch or comma community that's managed
by clique themselves and then you have
like a communities that only exist on
Stack Overflow for example for they is
Stack Overflow one where it has its own
life is it important that the the
company behind the software that they
are a part of that community not
necessarily if taking if it's so famous
that people are there and answering all
the questions and they are correct to
sponsors then I think the company has
succeeded in something really cool so
for me it would just tell me that yeah
this is a really good product people are
helping each other just because they
like it that's good this has also a
thing that's that's a time I first and
therefore money by the company that they
spend a lot of time I'm answering
community questions how important is it
that the company answers questions I
think it goes down to money question
area if it's if you can get I get by
without because there's a lot of people
are saying these things for you then
you're lucky you're a lucky company and
you don't need to do that
if it's not it's a niche product or if
it's you're struggling to get people to
work with and so on I think you have to
help people are get going if you're
going to create the community I think a
lot about what you you probably need to
have a seed the community strategy and
then you can back away if you think that
the communities is working by itself in
the beginning you probably need to be
there hmm so like just overall to put it
concise what what do you want from an
online community I think it's I want
answers to my questions I think that's
it so if I'm if further but if I'm
looking for different from evaluating
different products what I want for my
community is an active community I want
to see that's live there's good answers
to questions and it feels like then then
it's a plus in my decision mmm if I have
already decided or there's only one then
of course I have to make do with what I
have but then I have the same needs but
maybe I can have less more less because
I have to I have to use it so so let's
say that there was such a thing as a
flawless documentation would you still
need an online community not if I didn't
have any documentation gives all I need
mmm okay so yes that's also a any
company could invest energy in making
the community more alive or making API
documentation better so making the
documentation better it could replace a
community the need for a community you
say yeah
but the I think that is it's a little
bit dependent that area because it could
be really hard to provide examples which
are good enough for most people who
comes an interest area mm-hmm
while a community or more maybe if
they're willing they can put the
solution in perspective to the question
which a documentation couldn't do so if
you have an area which are very generic
for example you can do whatever with it
and then people come in are able to do
this fun stuff then I guess a community
could catch that person easier than our
documentation we should be very generic
in them okay don't really know if I can
do this or not
mmm the communique yeah of course you
can you just use these four or five
different calls and then something like
this and here's a very easy to see it so
in in reality they're do there is a need
of for an online community yeah if it's
a very generic product because you said
the perfect or perfect augmentation
would have a solution for requesting
you're kidding okay so so if but if you
step down to a more realistic approach
yes I think that our it exists there
exists companies and solutions which
would require community have any
questions for me or something you
thought I would ask that I didn't know I
think it was good at the Oscar what my
role was I think it's very important to
to steer it yeah but now getting that
perspective I think when I started
thinking here different actually so I
started answering for two different
perspective we just might be a little
bit confusing so maybe I should just
describe my previous row
I was a product owner and a little bit
of response over purchasing in my
current we're working purely know the
source more my role is more technical so
I have a large interest in solutions but
not purchasing decision since most
things are for free you know the source
and it's the technology which rules so
they are different somehow
these different roles mmm open-source
bird is actually complicating it a
little bit you don't have this
historically ok the manager stands for
the money and and the developers for
their so that might be something you can
pick up here yeah yes what I made it
clear your role as India we had a good
perspective from the nominal okay thanks